<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: common lisp | quasiTech]]></title>
  <link href="http://quasi.github.io/categories/common-lisp/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://quasi.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-05T19:27:34+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://quasi.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Abhijit Rao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Starting with Common Lisp]]></title>
    <link href="http://quasi.github.io/2014/02/05/starting-with-common-lisp/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-05T15:50:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://quasi.github.io/2014/02/05/starting-with-common-lisp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Learning a new programming language requires you to interact with its runtime. But the bare bones runtime is usually just that &ndash; bare. It generally is an unpleasant task to interact with directly. This is nowhere more true then when learning to program in Lisp. But the good news is that the tools of the Lisp environment are evolved and provide a lot of support to make interaction less unpleasent. It is therefore imperative that we use these tools and setup an ideal environment before we start with the lessons.</p>

<p>Today we will setup, <em>from scratch</em>, a <em>Common Lisp</em> development environment. This will include an editor, an interactive development environment, a structured editing mode and an implementation of Common Lisp.</p>

<p><em>Note : please change the paths in the examples to reflect your system</em></p>

<h4>Common Lisp</h4>

<p>We will need an implemntation of Common Lisp. There are <a href="http://cliki.net/Common%20Lisp%20implementation">several</a> free and commercial ones available. We will use the excellent public domain <a href="http://www.sbcl.org">Steel Bank Common Lisp (SBCL)</a> for this tutorial.</p>

<blockquote><p>Steel Bank Common Lisp (SBCL) is a high performance Common Lisp compiler. It is open source / free software, with a permissive license. In addition to the compiler and runtime system for ANSI Common Lisp, it provides an interactive environment including a debugger, a statistical profiler, a code coverage tool, and many other extensions.</p></blockquote>

<p>Let us select the Darwin (Mac OS X) AMD64 port from the <a href="http://www.sbcl.org/platform-table.html">downloads</a> section and download (&lt; 10 Mb).</p>

<p><code>
wget http://prdownloads.sourceforge.net/sbcl/sbcl-1.1.8-x86-64-darwin-binary.tar.bz2
</code>
Extract the archive
<code>
tar xjvf sbcl-1.1.8-x86-64-darwin-binary.tar.bz2
</code>
Change to the extracted folder
<code>
cd sbcl-1.1.8-x86-64-darwin
</code>
The <em>INSTALL</em> file details the installation instructions. I prefer to install in my home folder. Create a folder to contain all the <em>SBCL</em> files. Run the install script specifying the installation folder of our choice.
```
mkdir /Users/me/sbcl</p>

<p>INSTALL_ROOT=/Users/me/sbcl sh install.sh
<code>``
This will install all the files into</code>/Users/me/sbcl<code>. *SBCL* contains an executable and a core file. The executable - usually named</code>sbcl<code>- looks for an environment variable</code>SBCL_HOME` to locate the core file. We also need to set the locale. I have a shell script in my local bin which does all this.</p>

<p>Create a file <code>~/bin/sbcl</code> and add following to it :
```</p>

<h1>!/bin/sh</h1>

<p>LC_CTYPE=en_US.UTF-8
export LC_CTYPE
export SBCL_HOME=/Users/me/sbcl/lib/sbcl/</p>

<p>/Users/me/sbcl/bin/sbcl $*
<code>
Make this file executable
</code>
chmod +x ~/bin/sbcl
<code>
now typing `sbcl` into your shell prompt should start up *SBCL* and show something like below
</code>
This is SBCL 1.1.10, an implementation of ANSI Common Lisp.
More information about SBCL is available at <a href="http://www.sbcl.org/">http://www.sbcl.org/</a>.</p>

<p>SBCL is free software, provided as is, with absolutely no warranty.
It is mostly in the public domain; some portions are provided under
BSD-style licenses.  See the CREDITS and COPYING files in the
distribution for more information.
*
<code>
You can type s-expressions at the `*` prompt and the lisp will evaluate and return you an answer. For example.
</code>
* (+ 2 3)</p>

<p>5
*
```
Congrats !! We have an installed and running <em>Common Lisp</em> ! Now let&rsquo;s move forward.</p>

<h4>Quicklisp !</h4>

<p><a href="http://www.quicklisp.org/beta/">http://www.quicklisp.org/beta/</a> by Zach Beane</p>

<blockquote><p>Quicklisp is a library manager for Common Lisp. It works with your existing Common Lisp implementation to download, install, and load any of over 900 libraries with a few simple commands.</p></blockquote>

<p>Read through the installation instructions from that site. In short we will have to :</p>

<p><code>
$ curl -O http://beta.quicklisp.org/quicklisp.lisp
</code>
Start <em>SBCL</em> with this file :
<code>
sbcl --load quicklisp.lisp
</code>
At the prompt follow the instructions &ndash; type following :
<code>
* (quicklisp-quickstart:install)
</code>
This will download and install the latest <em>quicklisp</em> software. To add the <em>quicklisp</em> to the <em>SBCL</em> startup file :
<code>
(ql:add-to-init-file)
</code>
Now everytime you start <em>SBCL</em> it will load <em>quicklisp</em> automatically. yey!</p>

<p>To install a library you simply have to :
<code>
* (ql:quickload "libraryname")
</code></p>

<p>Now the we need to install a <em>very</em> important package called <a href="http://www.common-lisp.net/project/slime/">SLIME</a>. This is the software which gives us our interactive development environment <em>(like no other)</em> !</p>

<p><code>
(ql:quickload "quicklisp-slime-helper")
</code>
Note the instructions which follow this &ndash; you will need to use them for your editor configuration. Next topic.</p>

<h4>Editor</h4>

<blockquote><p>GNU Emacs is an extensible, customizable text editor—and more. At its core is an interpreter for Emacs Lisp, a dialect of the Lisp programming language with extensions to support text editing.</p></blockquote>

<p>Emacs is the editor of choice for Lisp programmers. It provides fantastic support for programming in various lisps. There are <a href="http://www.emacswiki.org/emacs/CategoryPorts">a lot of</a> flavours available for a lot of different systems. On GNU/Linux systems, the latest emacs can be installed using the system package manager. I use <a href="http://aquamacs.org">Aquamacs</a> on Mac OS X. Please install your Emacs before moving to the next step.</p>

<h4>Configuring Emacs</h4>

<p>Create a <code>.emacs</code> file in your home. This file is the Emacs startup file and can contain any valid elisp. All options can be configured here. By convention a folder <code>~/.emacs.d</code> is usually used for any misc elisp files, packages etc. which we may need to install manually.</p>

<p>Emacs comes with a package manager. This can automagically install packages and their dependencies. I like all the installed packages to reside inside a folder <code>.emacs.d/elpa</code>. Create this folder.  To set it up, add the following to your .emacs. (note : <code>;</code> start a comment in lisp source files)
```
(require &lsquo;package)
(add-to-list 'package-archives</p>

<pre><code>         '("melpa" . "http://melpa.milkbox.net/packages/") t)
</code></pre>

<p>(setq package-user-dir &ldquo;/Users/me/.emacs.d/elpa/&rdquo;) ;; change the path.
(package-initialize)
```</p>

<p>Now <code>M-x package-install &lt;package-name&gt;</code> will download and install the package.</p>

<h5>SLIME</h5>

<blockquote><p>SLIME is a Emacs mode for Common Lisp development.</p></blockquote>

<p>Configuring <em>SLIME</em> : Add the following to your .emacs
```
(setq inferior-lisp-program &ldquo;~/bin/sbcl&rdquo;)
(load (expand-file-name &ldquo;~/quicklisp/slime-helper.el&rdquo;))</p>

<p>(setq slime-lisp-implementations</p>

<pre><code>       '((sbcl ("~/bin/sbcl") :coding-system utf-8-unix)))
</code></pre>

<p>(set-language-environment &ldquo;UTF-8&rdquo;)
(setq slime-net-coding-system &lsquo;utf-8-unix)</p>

<p>```
This basically tells Emacs where to find the lisp (called <em>inferior-lisp</em>) program. Then we load the <em>slime-helper</em> which <em>quicklisp</em> provides.</p>

<p><code>M-x eval-buffer</code> will read your new changes. <code>M-x slime</code> should start <em>SLIME</em> and present you with a nice <em>REPL</em>. At the <em>REPL</em> <code>,q</code> will quit <em>SLIME</em>.</p>

<h5>PAREDIT</h5>

<blockquote><p>ParEdit (paredit.el) is a minor mode for performing structured editing of S-expression data.</p></blockquote>

<p><code>M-x package-install paredit</code> should download and install it.</p>

<p>To setup <em>paredit</em> and to get it to work with <em>SLIME</em>, add following to <code>.emacs</code>.
<code>
;; Paredit customizations
(autoload 'paredit-mode "paredit"
  "Minor mode for pseudo-structurally editing Lisp code."
  t)
(add-hook 'slime-mode-hook (lambda () (paredit-mode +1)))
(add-hook 'slime-repl-mode-hook (lambda () (paredit-mode +1)))
(require 'paredit)
</code></p>

<h4>Almost there</h4>

<p>At this point of time we have an installed and running Common Lisp implementation, an advanced editor, an interactive development environment &amp; a structured editing extention for the editor. This is the place to spend some time to see how all of these work.</p>

<ul>
<li>Inside Emacs <code>C-h t</code> starts the inbuilt interactive tutorial</li>
<li>Emacs introductory videos <a href="http://emacsrocks.com/">http://emacsrocks.com/</a></li>
<li><a href="http://common-lisp.net/project/movies/movies/slime.mov">SLIME video</a> &ndash; This is an excellent and instructional watch. Marco Baringer shows how it is done. Consider this also as informal introduction to SLIME</li>
<li>SLIME <a href="http://www.common-lisp.net/project/slime/doc/html/">manual</a></li>
<li>Paredit Author&rsquo;s <a href="http://mumble.net/~campbell/emacs/paredit.html">page</a></li>
<li>Paredit Emacs Wiki <a href="http://www.emacswiki.org/emacs/ParEdit">page</a></li>
</ul>


<h4>Epilogue : Learning Common Lisp</h4>

<p>Now that we have got all the boring setup stuff out of the way, let us <em>start</em> with Common Lisp !! <a href="http://www.gigamonkeys.com/book/">Practical Common Lisp</a> is an excellent modern introduction and you can start here.</p>

<p>I am assuming that as you have come this far, you <em>are</em> interested in learning. I would suggest that you do exactly so &ndash; <em>learn</em>. Give it some time and thought before you come to any conclusions. This is very important for people who are coming from a non-lisp programming background. The lisp way is different. It may take time for you to <em>get</em> it. Concentrate on the simpler language aspects and try to solve challenging programming problems. Stay away from the temptation of exploring libraries and doing some <em>&lsquo;real&rsquo;</em> work at this point. You will only get distracted with unnecessary detail.</p>

<p>Best Luck on your journey &ndash; You will not regret it.</p>

<p><em>May the force be with you.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I came to Lisp]]></title>
    <link href="http://quasi.github.io/2014/01/15/how-I-came-to-lisp/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-15T14:18:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://quasi.github.io/2014/01/15/how-I-came-to-lisp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p>This is the decade of <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23Lisp&amp;src=hash">#Lisp</a>. Mind it.</p>&mdash; Abhijit Rao (@_quasi) <a href="https://twitter.com/_quasi/statuses/365851774499815425">August 9, 2013</a></blockquote>


<script async src="http://quasi.github.io//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>People have asked me why I chose to program in Lisp.</p>

<h3>Early days</h3>

<p>Long back (1995-6) when I was still a college student (studying Math) I first saw Prolog. Chirs Martis, then boyfriend (now husband) of my friend Medha Patkar used to work for some company in SEEPZ and he was working on a project for some Japanese company. They had to migrate an older code base to a newer stack. I disremember the details (I dont think I knew much anyway) but he was learning Prolog as they were using a translater written in Prolog to help in the translation of the older codebase. I was a curious cuss then, and kept pestering him with questions. I was interested and wanted to learn Prolog. This was before we had access to the Internet. So my friend Anuprita took me to the British Council Library where she was a member. I saw a couple of Prolog books &ndash; pretty hard for me to understand as I had scant background in Programming (I did not even own a computer at that time). But I also saw a tiny booklet about another language called Lisp written by some Indian author. What intrigued me was the factorial program on the last page &ndash; this did not look like any program I had ever seen. I was more interested.</p>

<p>Fast forward to 1998. I tried using <a href="http://www.cons.org/cmucl/">CMUCL</a> on my AMD 386DX with 8 MB of RAM.  It was very hard to understand what to do at the REPL. Hardly any documentation.  Fast forward somewhere 2001 and Internet world. I landed up on comp.lang.lisp and asked a few silly questions. Got my head bitten off seriously &ndash; especially by Naggum. But <a href="http://xach.com/naggum/articles/">Erik Naggum</a>, and <a href="http://www.flownet.com/">Erann Gatt (Ron Garret)</a> were the reason I persisted. Erann(Ron) by his <a href="http://www.flownet.com/gat/jpl-lisp.html">Nasa stories</a> really awed me. By this time I had also come across <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greenspun%27s_Tenth_Rule">Greenspun&rsquo;s tenth rule</a> of programming&hellip;</p>

<p><img src="http://quasi.in/old-homepage/surreal/images/rmsandme.jpg" alt="RMS and me" /></p>

<p>By this time I was a super fan of <a href="http://stallman.org/">RMS</a>. He wrote <a href="http://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/">Emacs</a>. In <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emacs_Lisp">lisp</a>. WOW.</p>

<p>Soon, 2003, I wrote a software for a cable ISP service provider in Bandra East. I tried <a href="http://www.cons.org/cmucl/">CMUCL</a> again. This time with Emacs. I had an upgraded machine &ndash; Pentium MMX 200MHz with 32 MB or RAM. Those were the days when internet was provided by small players who provided Cable TV. This software did everything from user management to enabling / disabling users to keeping track of their usage. I used the GNU/Linux &lsquo;tc&rsquo; tool to do the traffic shaping. I wrote everything including a jazzy web-frontend in <a href="http://www.cons.org/cmucl/">CMUCL</a>. It ran very stably.</p>

<p>All this time I was a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Common_Lisp">Common Lisp</a> noob. But still I loved the simplicity of the syntax and the expressibility. There was also a sense that I was just touching the surface and I needed to find the horizon. From 1995 to this time I had learned programming in C and had done some low level stuff in Dos 6.22 and GNU/Linux. I had finished my Post Graduate Diploma in Networking from the National Center of Software Technology. I had done a bit of network programming. I loved to program in C. But I loved CL too.</p>

<p>So the reasons I persisted and learned programming in Common Lisp are many, mostly incidental. But there was also a sense that this was something beyond the ordinary &ndash; it was elegant. There was also some kind of respect for it as few of the greatest minds of this field had used it and respected it.</p>

<p>I had to explore. I had to learn.</p>

<p>next post &ndash; how I used Common Lisp at <a href="http://www.cleartrip.com/">Cleartrip</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pooler]]></title>
    <link href="http://quasi.github.io/2013/10/14/pooler/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-14T16:53:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://quasi.github.io/2013/10/14/pooler</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A <em>simple</em>, <em>fast</em> &amp; <em>thread-safe</em> generic pooling library.</p>

<p>Homepage <a href="http://quasilabs.com/pooler/">http://quasilabs.com/pooler/</a></p>

<p>We need pools for items which have heavy cost of creation and which we can reuse. A typical use case is connection pools.</p>

<p>Pool item creation (as required) is automatic on fetch-from pool. Pool-item&rsquo;s are created and destroyed using user supplied funcitons. The pool has a idle timeout after which all the existing pool-item&rsquo;s are destroyed and new ones created (pool-init). The pool has a threshold number of items which it tries to maintain.</p>

<p>Licence : MIT</p>

<p>An Example :
```
CL-USER> (pooler:make-pool :item-maker</p>

<pre><code>                       #'(lambda () (clsql:connect '("127.0.0.1" "quasidb" "quasi" "*****")
                                                   :database-type :mysql
                                                   :if-exists :new))
                       :item-destroyer
                       #'(lambda (item) (clsql:disconnect :database item)))
</code></pre>

<h1>S(POOLER::POOL</h1>

<p>  :NAME &ldquo;Default Pool&rdquo;
  :QUEUE #S(SB-CONCURRENCY:QUEUE
  :HEAD (SB-CONCURRENCY::.DUMMY.)
  :TAIL (SB-CONCURRENCY::.DUMMY.)
  :NAME NIL)
  :LOCK #&lt;SB-THREAD:MUTEX &ldquo;Pool Lock&rdquo; (free)>
  :ITEM-MAKER #<FUNCTION (LAMBDA #) {1005C9BFAB}>
  :ITEM-DESTROYER #<FUNCTION (LAMBDA #) {1005CCAAAB}>
  :CAPACITY 40
  :THRESHOLD 2
  :TIMEOUT 300
  :LAST-ACCESS 0
  :CURRENT-SIZE 0
  :TOTAL-USES 0
  :TOTAL-CREATED 0
  :TOTAL-POOL-INITS 0)
CL-USER> (defvar <em>mysql-pool</em> <em>)
CL-USER> (pooler:fetch-from </em>mysql-pool*)</p>

<h1>&lt;CLSQL-MYSQL:MYSQL-DATABASE 127.0.0.1/quasidb/quasi OPEN {1007571373}></h1>

<p>CL-USER> (pooler:return-to <em>mysql-pool</em> <em>)
2
CL-USER> (pooler:with-pool (db </em>mysql-pool*) (clsql:query &ldquo;show tables;&rdquo; :database db))
((&ldquo;LOGIN_DATA&rdquo;))
(&ldquo;Tables_in_quasidb&rdquo;)
```</p>

<p>Has been tested with <a href="http://www.sbcl.org/">SBCL</a>, <a href="http://www.clozure.com/clozurecl.html">CCL</a> &amp; <a href="http://www.cons.org/cmucl/">CMUCL</a> on OSX. Should work on GNU/Linux.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Hash Functions]]></title>
    <link href="http://quasi.github.io/2009/03/21/hash-functions/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-21T14:20:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://quasi.github.io/2009/03/21/hash-functions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here are some common hash functions in C I found online <a href="http://www.cse.yorku.ca/~oz/hash.html">here</a> and <a href="http://www.partow.net/programming/hashfunctions/index.html">here</a>. I have done the menial task of translating them to Common Lisp.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='common-lisp'><span class='line'><span class="c1">;;; Hash Function by Dan Bernstein</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">defun</span> <span class="nv">hash-DJB</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">str</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">(</span><span class="k">declare</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="k">type</span> <span class="kt">simple-string</span> <span class="nv">str</span><span class="p">)</span><span class="nv">&lt;/p&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="k">type</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="kt">unsigned-byte</span> <span class="mi">32</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="nv">hash</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">(</span><span class="k">optimize</span> <span class="nv">speed</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">debug</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">)))</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;p&gt;</span>  <span class="p">(</span><span class="k">let</span> <span class="p">((</span><span class="nv">hash</span> <span class="mi">5381</span><span class="p">))</span><span class="nv">&lt;/p&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">loop</span> <span class="nv">for</span> <span class="nv">x</span> <span class="nv">across</span> <span class="nv">str</span>
</span><span class='line'> <span class="nb">do</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">setf</span> <span class="nv">hash</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">ldb</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">byte</span> <span class="mi">32</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>                    <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">+</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">ldb</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">byte</span> <span class="mi">32</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>                            <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">+</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">ldb</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">byte</span> <span class="mi">32</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>                                    <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">ash</span> <span class="nv">hash</span> <span class="mi">5</span><span class="p">))</span> <span class="nv">hash</span><span class="p">))</span>
</span><span class='line'>                       <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">char-int</span> <span class="nv">x</span><span class="p">))))</span>
</span><span class='line'> <span class="nv">finally</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">return</span> <span class="nv">hash</span><span class="p">))))</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;p&gt;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='common-lisp'><span class='line'><span class="c1">;;; Hash Function by Dan Bernstein</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">defun</span> <span class="nv">hash-DJB2</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">str</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">(</span><span class="k">declare</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="k">type</span> <span class="kt">simple-string</span> <span class="nv">str</span><span class="p">)</span><span class="nv">&lt;/p&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="k">type</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="kt">unsigned-byte</span> <span class="mi">32</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="nv">hash</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">(</span><span class="k">optimize</span> <span class="nv">speed</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">debug</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">)))</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;p&gt;</span>  <span class="p">(</span><span class="k">let</span> <span class="p">((</span><span class="nv">hash</span> <span class="mi">5381</span><span class="p">))</span><span class="nv">&lt;/p&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">loop</span> <span class="nv">for</span> <span class="nv">x</span> <span class="nv">across</span> <span class="nv">str</span>
</span><span class='line'>   <span class="nb">do</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">setf</span> <span class="nv">hash</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">ldb</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">byte</span> <span class="mi">32</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>                      <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">logxor</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">char-int</span> <span class="nv">x</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">*</span> <span class="nv">hash</span> <span class="mi">33</span><span class="p">))))</span>
</span><span class='line'>   <span class="nv">finally</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">return</span> <span class="nv">hash</span><span class="p">))))</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;p&gt;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='common-lisp'><span class='line'><span class="c1">;;; Hash Function from GAWK, a variation from the verwion from SDBM</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">defun</span> <span class="nv">hash-SDBM</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">str</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">(</span><span class="k">declare</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="k">type</span> <span class="kt">simple-string</span> <span class="nv">str</span><span class="p">)</span><span class="nv">&lt;/p&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;</span>       <span class="p">(</span><span class="k">type</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="kt">unsigned-byte</span> <span class="mi">32</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="nv">hash</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>       <span class="p">(</span><span class="k">optimize</span> <span class="nv">speed</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">debug</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">)))</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;p&gt;</span>  <span class="p">(</span><span class="k">let</span> <span class="p">((</span><span class="nv">hash</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">))</span><span class="nv">&lt;/p&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">loop</span> <span class="nv">for</span> <span class="nv">x</span> <span class="nv">across</span> <span class="nv">str</span>
</span><span class='line'>   <span class="nb">do</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">setf</span> <span class="nv">hash</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">ldb</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">byte</span> <span class="mi">32</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>                      <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">+</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">char-int</span> <span class="nv">x</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>                         <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">ldb</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">byte</span> <span class="mi">32</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">ash</span> <span class="nv">hash</span> <span class="mi">6</span><span class="p">))</span>
</span><span class='line'>                         <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">ldb</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">byte</span> <span class="mi">32</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">ash</span> <span class="nv">hash</span> <span class="mi">16</span><span class="p">))</span>
</span><span class='line'>                         <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">-</span> <span class="nv">hash</span><span class="p">))))</span>
</span><span class='line'>   <span class="nv">finally</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">return</span> <span class="nv">hash</span><span class="p">))))</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;p&gt;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='common-lisp'><span class='line'><span class="c1">;;; An algorithm proposed by Donald E. Knuth in The Art Of Computer Programming Volume 3</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">defun</span> <span class="nv">hash-DEK</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">str</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">(</span><span class="k">declare</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="k">type</span> <span class="kt">simple-string</span> <span class="nv">str</span><span class="p">)</span><span class="nv">&lt;/p&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;</span>   <span class="p">(</span><span class="k">type</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="kt">unsigned-byte</span> <span class="mi">32</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="nv">hash</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>   <span class="p">(</span><span class="k">optimize</span> <span class="nv">speed</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">debug</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">)))</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;p&gt;</span>  <span class="p">(</span><span class="k">let</span> <span class="p">((</span><span class="nv">hash</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">length</span> <span class="nv">str</span><span class="p">)))</span><span class="nv">&lt;/p&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">loop</span> <span class="nv">for</span> <span class="nv">x</span> <span class="nv">across</span> <span class="nv">str</span>
</span><span class='line'>   <span class="nb">do</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">setf</span> <span class="nv">hash</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">ldb</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">byte</span> <span class="mi">32</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>                      <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">logxor</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">char-int</span> <span class="nv">x</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>                              <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">logxor</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">ldb</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">byte</span> <span class="mi">32</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">ash</span> <span class="nv">hash</span> <span class="mi">5</span><span class="p">))</span>
</span><span class='line'>                                      <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">ash</span> <span class="nv">hash</span> <span class="mi">-27</span><span class="p">)))))</span>
</span><span class='line'>   <span class="nv">finally</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">return</span> <span class="nv">hash</span><span class="p">))))</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">&lt;p&gt;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
